<chapter id="cfg">
	<title>Configuration</title>

	<para>
		Configuring J-Ben is done through the Configuration tab. Currently all
		options pertain to the kanji dictionary. Later versions will have
		options to control many more things, such as word dictionary output,
		fonts, and paths to the dictionary files used (which is especially
		important on Linux).
	</para>
	<sect1>
		<title>Configuring the Kanji Dictionary</title>

		<para>
			Most configuration options have to do with the various data
			contained within KANJIDIC. KANJIDIC has tons of information, and
			much of it is overkill for the purpose of most students. A set of
			fairly sane defaults are chosen, but you can modify these as
			necessary. Most options are self-explanatory.
		</para>

		<para>
			If you own a paper kanji dictionary, or a set of kanji flash cards,
			you may want to check through the dictionary reference codes. Index
			codes for many dictionaries and several flash card sets are
			included. For example, I personally use the Kodansha Kanji
			Learner's Dictionary by Jack Halpern, so I usually have this code
			enabled so I can very easily reference it if I'm not satisfied with
			the output of KANJIDIC.
		</para>

		<para>
			If you set up a <link linkend="vsl">vocab study list</link>, then
			there's a useful option to display words in your vocab list which
			use the kanji you're looking up. This option is strongly
			recommended. If there's nothing in your study list, or nothing that
			matches your search, then this option doesn't display any extra
			information.
		</para>

		<para>
			The "other information" option is for the various other "excessive"
			data contained in KANJIDIC but which I feel most Japanese learners
			usually will not need. This includes JIS and Unicode hex codes,
			various radical index numbers, Korean and "Pinyin" romanizations,
			dictionary cross-reference codes, and any other KANJIDIC fields not
			handled elsewhere.
		</para>

		<para>
			Finally, if you install one or more of the KanjiCafe.com stroke
			order diagram packs, you can toggle whether to show them here.
		</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
