<chapter id="prefs">
  <title>Preferences editor</title>

  <para>
    Configuring J-Ben is done through the Preferences editor.  Currently,
    you can configure the kanji dictionary, the display fonts, and J-Ben's
    mobile/standard mode.
  </para>
  <sect1 id="prefs_kdict">
    <title>Configuring the kanji dictionary</title>

    <para>
      Most configuration options have to do with the various data
      contained within KANJIDIC. KANJIDIC has tons of information, and
      much of it is overkill for the purpose of most students. A set of
      fairly sane defaults are chosen, but you can modify these as
      necessary. Most options are self-explanatory.
    </para>

    <para>
      If you own a paper kanji dictionary, or a set of kanji flash cards,
      you may want to check through the dictionary reference codes. Index
      codes for many dictionaries and several flash card sets are
      included. For example, I personally use the Kodansha Kanji
      Learner's Dictionary by Jack Halpern, so I usually have this code
      enabled so I can very easily reference it if I'm not satisfied with
      the output of KANJIDIC.
    </para>

    <para>
      If you set up a <link linkend="vsl">vocab study list</link>, then
      there's a useful option to display words in your vocab list which
      use the kanji you're looking up. This option is strongly
      recommended. If there's nothing in your study list, or nothing that
      matches your search, then this option doesn't display any extra
      information.
    </para>

    <para>
      The "other information" option is for the various other "excessive"
      data contained in KANJIDIC but which I feel most Japanese learners
      usually will not need. This includes JIS and Unicode hex codes,
      various radical index numbers, Korean and "Pinyin" romanizations,
      dictionary cross-reference codes, and any other KANJIDIC fields not
      handled elsewhere.
    </para>

    <para>
      Finally, if you install one or more of the KanjiCafe.com stroke
      order diagram packs, you can toggle whether to show them here.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="prefs_kanjidrill">
    <title>Configuring kanji tests</title>

    <para>
      A few options are available for modifying the behavior of kanji tests.
      You can select, for both "reading" and "writing" modes, which information
      fields you want shown or covered.  Additionally, single-key keyboard
      shortcuts are supported, allowing you to easily drill using only one
      hand on the keyboard (and the other hand writing kanji on paper, hopefully).
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="prefs_fonts">
    <title>Configuring the display fonts</title>

    <para>
      J-Ben uses four special fonts for displaying text in the program.
      Here, you can change how they are set.  Each font is described
      below.
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Japanese Font, Normal: General purpose Japanese display
	font.  Used for most Japanese text display throughout the program.</listitem>
      <listitem>Japanese Font, Large: Used for displaying the "header"
	character in kanji dictionary output.</listitem>
      <listitem>English Font, Normal: General purpose English font.  Used
	for dictionary output and some other places where Japanese is not
	expected.</listitem>
      <listitem>English Font, Small: Used for displaying
	disclaimer/copyright related text in some places.</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="prefs_other">
    <title>Other options</title>

    <para>
      Currently only one "other option" is supported: the J-Ben "mobile
      mode" toggle.  As mentioned earlier, this simply adjusts where
      J-Ben's configuration file(s) are saved.  If mobile mode is
      checked, then settings will be saved based upon the working directory.
      Usually, this means that it'll save to the program's root folder,
      which is ideal for USB thumb drives.  If mobile mode is not checked,
      then J-Ben will save to the user's "home" or "Application Data"
      folder.
    </para>
    <para>
      (Note for Linux users: mobile mode is currently a Windows-only
      option.  Also, because of this, you probably will not have an
      "Other" tab.)
    </para>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
