<chapter>
	<title>General Usage</title>
	<sect1>
		<title>The Dictionaries</title>

		<para>
			J-Ben provides a bidirectional word dictionary and a kanji
			(character) dictionary. These dictionaries are dependent upon the
			freely available EDICT2 and KANJIDIC dictionary files from Monash
			University.
		</para>

		<sect2>
			<title>The Word Dictionary</title>
			<para>
				The word dictionary performs a very simple search based upon the
				ENTIRE QUERY - it doesn't try to match all the words or some of
				the words, but rather treats your query as a phrase and matches
				only the whole phrase. Results are arranged with exact matches
				first, followed by "begins with" matches, "ends with" matches,
				and finally, everything else. Japanese searches work best
				because of the structure of EDICT2, but English searches work
				fairly well as well.
			</para>

			<para>
				The word dictionary ties into the <link linkend="vsl">vocab
				study list</link>. You can step through or jump to a random word
				in your vocab list using the buttons at the bottom of the
				dictionary tab.
			</para>
		</sect2>

		<sect2>
			<title>The Kanji (Character) Dictionary</title>
			<para>
				The kanji dictionary searches for one or more kanji characters
				and displays detailed information about each one. Because of
				the amount of data available for each character, and because
				most people don't need much of the data available, the output
				can be customized through the <link linkend="cfg">configuration
				tab</link>.
			</para>
			<para>
				Information provided includes the following:
			</para>
			<para>
				The kanji dictionary can be supplemented with kanji stroke order
				diagrams. J-Ben is licensed to use the 3rd public release of
				the
				<ulink url="http://www.kanjicafe.com/using_soder.htm">SODER
				project</ulink>'s stroke order diagrams, however to save on
				download size these are not included in the main J-Ben packages.
				They are available from the
				<ulink url="http://www.vultaire.net/software/jben/download.php">
				J-Ben download page</ulink> along with the rest of the J-Ben
				packages. Download one of these packages and decompress it into
				the "sods" directory of J-Ben. If there is no "sods" directory,
				create one. Then, in the <link linkend="cfs">configuration
				tab</link>, enable either regular or animated stroke order
				diagrams, and you should be set. (As a last note, packages
				directly from KanjiCafe can also be used, but they need marked
				as utf8-hex.)
			</para>

			<para>
				The kanji dictionary ties into both the <link
				linkend="ksl">kanji</link> and <link linkend="vsl">vocab study
				list</link>s. You can move through your kanji study list using
				the forward, backward, and random buttons at the bottom of the
				dictionary tab. Further, if you search for a single kanji and
				it is in your list, the dictionary will recognize this and
				allow you to step through your list from the current character.
				Finally, all character searches are cross-referenced with your
				vocab study list, and if any of your vocab contain the kanji,
				they will be listed as well.
			</para>
		</sect2>

	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Kanji Drilling</title>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Study Lists</title>
		<sect2 id="ksl">
			<title>The Kanji Study List</title>

			<para>Blah de blah, used by this, used by that.</para>

			<sect3>
				<title>Adding characters to the list</title>
			</sect3>

			<sect3>
				<title>Managing the list</title>
			</sect3>

			<sect3>
				<title>Exporting and importing study lists</title>
			</sect3>

		</sect2>
		<sect2 id="vsl">
			<title>The Vocab Study List</title>

			<para>
				Blah de blah, used by these things, edited in this way,	done.
			</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
