<chapter>
  <title>General usage</title>
  <sect1>
    <title>The main interface</title>

    <para>
      J-Ben's main window has two tabs, providing a bidirectional word
      dictionary and a kanji (character) dictionary. These dictionaries
      are dependent upon the various dictionary files (EDICT2,
      KANJIDIC/KANJD212/KANJIDIC2, KRADFILE/RADKFILE) freely available
      from Monash University on
      <ulink url="http://www.csse.monash.edu.au/~jwb/japanese.html">Jim Breen's homepage</ulink>.
    </para>

    <sect2>
      <title>The word dictionary</title>
      <para>
	The word dictionary performs a very simple search based upon the
	ENTIRE QUERY - it doesn't try to match all the words or some of
	the words, but rather treats your query as a phrase and matches
	only the whole phrase. Results are arranged with exact matches
	first, followed by "begins with" matches, "ends with" matches,
	and finally, everything else. Japanese searches work best
	because of the structure of EDICT2, but English searches work
	fairly well as well.
      </para>

      <para>
	The word dictionary ties into the <link linkend="vsl">vocab
	  study list</link>. You can step through or jump to a random word
	in your vocab list using the buttons at the bottom of the
	dictionary tab.
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="kdict">
      <title>The kanji (character) dictionary</title>

      <para>
	The kanji dictionary searches for one or more kanji characters
	and displays detailed information about each one. Because of
	the amount of data available for each character, and because
	most people don't need much of the data available, the output
	can be customized through the <link linkend="prefs">preferences
	  editor</link>.
      </para>

      <para>
	Information provided includes (but is not limited to) the
	following:
      </para>

      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>Japanese-style readings (kun-yomi) and
	  "Chinese-style" sound-based readings (on-yomi)</listitem>
	<listitem>Special readings for use in names
	  (nanori)</listitem>
	<listitem>Stroke count</listitem>
	<listitem>Jouyou grade level</listitem>
	<listitem>Dictionary reference codes</listitem>
	<listitem>Korean and "Pinyin" readings</listitem>
	<listitem>JIS and Unicode values in hexadecimal</listitem>
	<listitem>Various radical information</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>
	Display of stroke order diagrams can be toggled here. This is
	dependent upon <link linkend="kksod_install">installing a set of
	  stroke order diagrams</link>.
      </para>

      <para>
	The kanji dictionary ties into both the <link linkend="ksl">kanji</link>
	and <link linkend="vsl">vocab study lists</link>. You can move through
	your kanji study list using
	the forward, backward, and random buttons at the bottom of the
	dictionary tab. Further, if you search for a single kanji and
	it is in your list, the dictionary will recognize this and
	allow you to step through your list from the current character.
	Finally, all character searches are cross-referenced with your
	vocab study list, and if any of your vocab contain the kanji,
	they will be listed as well.
      </para>
    </sect2>

  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Kanji search</title>

    <para>If you do not know how to type a kanji, or are unable to, J-Ben has
      two methods to allow you to look kanji up and copy them to the
      clipboard.</para>

    <para>The first method is handwriting recognition.  This is available via
      the menu item "Tools->Handwriting Recognition for Kanji".  Using this,
      draw the character using your mouse.  As you draw the character, the
      window will show you the 5 best matches for what you have drawn.  This
      method uses the database from JStroke/KanjiPad/im-ja, and at last count
      supports searching for 2116 characters.</para>

    <para>The second method is the new integrated kanji search, available via
      "Tools->Kanji Search".  This method allows you to choose one or more
      search methods to quickly find kanji.  These search methods all use the
      standard dictionary files, with the exception of handwriting recognition
      as previously described.</para>

    <para>The integrated search currently supports the following search methods:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Stroke count.  Allows for including common
	miscounts and a +/- search range.</listitem>
      <listitem>SKIP code, as used in Halpern dictionaries.  (An
	explanation can be found
	<ulink url="http://www.csse.monash.edu.au/~jwb/SKIP.html">here</ulink>.)
	Allows wildcard searches by specifying "0" as any of the 3
	index numbers.  Also allows a +/- search range, which is
	applied to both the second and third index.</listitem>
      <listitem>Handwriting Recognition.  This is functionally
	identical to that provided by the standalone handwriting
	"pad", but can also be used through this
	interface.</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>All selected search methods are applied together, from top to bottom.</para>

    <para>More methods will be added in future versions.  My highest priority
      is multiradical search support as seen in JWP/JWPce/Gjiten/WWWJDIC.
      Other methods will be added as requested by users and as time
      allows.</para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1 id="kdrill">
    <title>Kanji drilling</title>

    <para>J-Ben provides an easy-to-use kanji "flash card" mode.  This can be
      accessed via the "Practice->Kanji" menu item.  It requires that you
      define a <link linkend="ksl">kanji study list</link> before using it.</para>

    <para>The kanji practice mode is intended as a basic self-study tool, and
      does not ask you to input any answers to questions or anything similar.
      It will display information about a kanji with some of the information
      hidden from view, and it is your job to guess, either mentally or on a
      separate sheet of paper, what the missing information is. After doing
      this, you can look at the hidden fields, and you decide for yourself
      whether or not you remembered the character properly or not.</para>

    <para>This is a self-graded test; you decide for each character whether
      you got it "Correct" or "Wrong", and the program will simply track your
      answers and help you study the ones you had trouble with.  The program
      will continue to drill you through the characters you mark as "Wrong",
      and at the end of the test will present you with a score and a list of
      the characters you got wrong.</para>

    <para>
      The first step in using this mode is to select which characters to
      test yourself on. You start by choosing how many characters you
      want to test, and then you pick whether to select the kanji randomly
      from your list or in order from a certain index of your list. The
      former method may be better for general review, while the latter
      would be good for practicing through sets of new characters in your
      list.
    </para>

    <para>
      The second step is choosing the type of test. If you want to
      practice writing characters by hand, you will probably want to try
      the "writing kanji" option. However, if just reading the characters
      is sufficient, which may be fairly true if you only read or type
      Japanese, then you might be better served focusing on "reading
      kanji".
    </para>

    <para>
      After clicking "Start Drill", test mode begins. While in test mode,
      any active dictionary searches will be cleared, and you will be
      unable to access the word and kanji dictionaries until you finish.
      The screen will display 4 textboxes containing information about the
      kanji: the character itself, its on-yomi (sound-based) reading, its
      kun-yomi (Japanese style) reading, and its meaning in English.
      Some of the textboxes will be covered up, depending on which test
      mode you chose: for "writing kanji" only the kanji character is
      covered by default, while for "reading kanji" everything except the
      kanji character is covered. You can uncover each of the textboxes simply
      by clicking on them, or you can uncover all of them by pressing the
      "Show Answer" button.  (Clicking "Show Answer" in "writing kanji" mode
      will also show a stroke order diagram for the kanji, if present.)
      After reviewing each flash card, you choose
      whether you got it "Correct" or "Wrong", and then the program will
      go to the next card in your list.
    </para>

    <para>
      After running through all of the flash cards, if you marked any of
      them as wrong, the program will continue to drill you through the
      ones you missed.  At this point your score won't change; this is
      just extra practice and if you want you can click "Stop Test" to
      skip it.  I recommend running through this, though.  The extra
      review ends once you've marked each kanji as "Correct".
    </para>

    <para>
      At the end of the test (or if you select "Stop Test"), the Test
      Results message box will appear.  It will tell you what your score
      was, how much of the test you finished, and which kanji you missed,
      if any.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Study lists</title>
    <sect2 id="ksl">
      <title>The kanji study list</title>

      <para>
	The kanji study list is used for storing any kanji characters
	you are studying. It's used by the <link linkend="kdict">kanji
	  dictionary</link> and is required for
	<link linkend="kdrill">kanji drilling mode</link>. This list
	can be added to and sorted based on newspaper frequency and
	Jouyou grade level.
      </para>

      <sect3>
	<title>Adding characters to the list</title>

	<para>
	  If you don't know where to start on studying kanji, I
	  personally recommend using the Kanji menu to add kanji to
	  your list by Jouyou grade level. This is done by selecting
	  Kanji -&gt; Add Kanji to List -&gt; By Jouyou Grade Level,
	  and selecting a range of grades to add from the dialog which
	  appears. Alternatively, you can select By Newspaper
	  Frequency Ranking and choose kanji to add in that way.
	</para>

	<para>
	  Alternatively, you can <link linkend="klistimport">import a
	    list from a text file</link>, or you can <link
							linkend="klistedit">manually edit the list</link> using the
	  Kanji Study List editor.
	</para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="klistimport">
	<title>Importing study lists</title>

	<para>
	  The "Add Kanji From File" button will let you import a plain
	  text file into J-Ben, from which all the kanji characters
	  will be detected and added to your study list.  The text
	  file must be encoded in UTF-8.  If you are unsure about this,
	  it is probably safer to just copy and paste the file directly
	  into the editor window and then press Apply.
	</para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="klistedit">
	<title>Manually editing the list</title>

	<para>
	  The Kanji Study List editor lets you manually edit your kanji
	  list. You can type kanji in by hand, or copy and paste them
	  from another application.  This editor is accessible via
	  "Edit->Kanji Study List".
	</para>

	<para>
	  When you hit the Commit button, your changes are saved.
	  Only kanji which are in the kanji dictionary will be
	  retained; any other characters are discarded. Duplicates
	  are also automatically removed. So, you could simply copy
	  and paste a vocab list into the kanji list editor, hit
	  commit, and you would end up with a list of all the kanji
	  used in that list.
	</para>

	<para>
	  If you don't like the changes you've made, just hit the
	  Revert button, and the list will return to the way it was.
	</para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3>
	<title>Sorting the list</title>

	<para>
	  After adding characters to the list, it is strongly
	  recommended to sort the list.  The editor allows 3 methods
	  of sorting: by Jouyou grade level, by newspaper frequency,
	  or by both (using an outer sort by grade level and an inner
	  sort by newspaper frequency).  Currently you can only sort
	  in ascending order.
	</para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="klistclear">
	<title>Clearing the study list</title>

	<para>
	  All operations on the kanji list are additive: even
	  importing a list from a file doesn't replace the list, but
	  rather just adds to it. In the case you actually want to
	  replace the current kanji list with another, or just start
	  from scratch, select Clear Kanji List from the Kanji menu.
	</para>
      </sect3>

    </sect2>
    <sect2 id="vsl">
      <title>The vocab study list</title>

      <para>
	The vocab study list can be edited via the "Edit->Vocab Study
	List" menu item.  This study list is primarily used as a
	cross-referencing resource for the kanji dictionary.  The list
	is formatted with each line representing one Japanese word or
	phrase. Either manually type in the list, or copy and
	paste it from another program, and press Apply or OK.
      </para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
</chapter>
