<chapter>
	<title>General Usage</title>
	<sect1>
		<title>The Dictionaries</title>

		<para>
			J-Ben provides a bidirectional word dictionary and a kanji
			(character) dictionary. These dictionaries are dependent upon the
			freely available EDICT2 and KANJIDIC dictionary files from Monash
			University.
		</para>

		<sect2>
			<title>The Word Dictionary</title>
			<para>
				The word dictionary performs a very simple search based upon the
				ENTIRE QUERY - it doesn't try to match all the words or some of
				the words, but rather treats your query as a phrase and matches
				only the whole phrase. Results are arranged with exact matches
				first, followed by "begins with" matches, "ends with" matches,
				and finally, everything else. Japanese searches work best
				because of the structure of EDICT2, but English searches work
				fairly well as well.
			</para>

			<para>
				The word dictionary ties into the <link linkend="vsl">vocab
				study list</link>. You can step through or jump to a random word
				in your vocab list using the buttons at the bottom of the
				dictionary tab.
			</para>
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id="kdict">
			<title>The Kanji (Character) Dictionary</title>
			<para>
				The kanji dictionary searches for one or more kanji characters
				and displays detailed information about each one. Because of
				the amount of data available for each character, and because
				most people don't need much of the data available, the output
				can be customized through the <link linkend="cfg">configuration
				tab</link>.
			</para>
			<para>
				Information provided includes the following:
			</para>
			<para>
				The kanji dictionary can be supplemented with kanji stroke order
				diagrams. J-Ben is licensed to use the 3rd public release of
				the
				<ulink url="http://www.kanjicafe.com/using_soder.htm">SODER
				project</ulink>'s stroke order diagrams, however to save on
				download size these are not included in the main J-Ben packages.
				They are available from the
				<ulink url="http://www.vultaire.net/software/jben/download.php">
				J-Ben download page</ulink> along with the rest of the J-Ben
				packages. Download one of these packages and decompress it into
				the "sods" directory of J-Ben. If there is no "sods" directory,
				create one. Then, in the <link linkend="cfs">configuration
				tab</link>, enable either regular or animated stroke order
				diagrams, and you should be set. (As a last note, packages
				directly from KanjiCafe can also be used, but they need marked
				as utf8-hex.)
			</para>

			<para>
				The kanji dictionary ties into both the <link
				linkend="ksl">kanji</link> and <link linkend="vsl">vocab study
				list</link>s. You can move through your kanji study list using
				the forward, backward, and random buttons at the bottom of the
				dictionary tab. Further, if you search for a single kanji and
				it is in your list, the dictionary will recognize this and
				allow you to step through your list from the current character.
				Finally, all character searches are cross-referenced with your
				vocab study list, and if any of your vocab contain the kanji,
				they will be listed as well.
			</para>
		</sect2>

	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="kdrill">
		<title>Kanji Drilling</title>

		<para>
			- To be written -
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Study Lists</title>
		<sect2 id="ksl">
			<title>The Kanji Study List</title>

			<para>
				The kanji study list is used for storing any kanji characters
				you are studying. It's used by the <link linkend="kdict">kanji
				dictionary</link> and is required for
				<link linkend="kdrill">kanji drilling mode</link>. This list
				can be added to and sorted based on newspaper frequency and
				Jouyou grade level.
			</para>

			<sect3>
				<title>Adding characters to the list</title>

				<para>
					If you don't know where to start on studying kanji, I
					personally recommend using the Kanji menu to add kanji to
					your list by Jouyou grade level. This is done by selecting
					Kanji -&gt; Add Kanji to List -&gt; By Jouyou Grade Level,
					and selecting a range of grades to add from the dialog which
					appears. Alternatively, you can select By Newspaper
					Frequency Ranking and choose kanji to add in that way.
				</para>

				<para>
					Alternatively, you can <link linkend="klistimport">import a
					list from a text file</link>, or you can <link
					linkend="klistedit">manually edit the list</link> using the
					Kanji Study List tab.
				</para>
			</sect3>

			<sect3 id="klistedit">
				<title>Manually editing the list</title>

				<para>
					The Kanji Study List tab lets you manually edit your kanji
					list. You can type kanji in by hand, or copy and paste them
					from another application.
				</para>

				<para>
					When you hit the Commit button, your changes are saved.
					Only kanji which are in the kanji dictionary will be
					retained; any other characters are discarded. Duplicates
					are also automatically removed. So, you could simply copy
					and paste a vocab list into the kanji list editor, hit
					commit, and you would end up with a list of all the kanji
					used in that list.
				</para>

				<para>
					If you don't like the changes you've made, just hit the
					Revert button, and the list will return to the way it was.
				</para>
			</sect3>

			<sect3>
				<title>Sorting the list</title>

				<para>
					After adding characters to the list, it is strongly
					recommended to sort the list.  Via the Kanji -&gt; Sort
					Kanji in List menu, you can sort your current study list by
					Jouyou grade level and newspaper frequency ranking.
					Currently you can only sort in ascending order.
				</para>

				<para>
					Personally, I like to apply both sorting methods.  First I
					sort by newspaper ranking, so that the most common
					characters are first in the list.  Next, I sort by Jouyou
					level.  This will sort the characters from the lowest
					Jouyou level to the highest (with uncategorized characters
					at the very end).  However, within the grade levels it will
					maintain the newspaper frequency sort, meaning that as I
					study each grade level, I'm exposed to the likely more
					important characters first.
				</para>
			</sect3>

			<sect3 id="klistimport">
				<title>Exporting and importing study lists</title>

				<para>
					The current kanji list can be exported to a plain text file
					using the Kanji -&gt; Save Kanji List to File... menu.
					Likewise, this text file (or any other plain text file) can
					be imported using the Kanji -&gt; Add Kanji to List -> From
					File... menu.  However, you may want to <link
					linkend="klistclear">clear the study list</link> first.
				</para>
			</sect3>

			<sect3 id="klistclear">
				<title>Clearing the study list</title>

				<para>
					All operations on the kanji list are additive: even
					importing a list from a file doesn't replace the list, but
					rather just adds to it.  In the case you actually want to
					replace the current kanji list with another, or just start
					from scratch, select Clear Kanji List from the Kanji menu.
				</para>
			</sect3>

		</sect2>
		<sect2 id="vsl">
			<title>The Vocab Study List</title>

			<para>
				The vocab study list is a newer feature and is primarily used
				as as cross-referencing resource for the kanji dictionary. Due
				to its lower importance, there is currently only one way to edit
				this list, and that is through the Words -&gt; Study List tab.
				The list is formatted with each line representing one Japanese
				word or phrase. Either manually type in the list, or copy and
				paste it from another program, and press Commit. That's it!
			</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
